<root>
<Bwords>
<w>
<name>BAIL</name>
<meaning>Money or other security (such as a bail bond) provided to the court to temporarily allow a person's release from jail and assure his or her appearance in court. Bail and Bond are often used interchangeably</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAIL BOND</name>
<meaning>An obligation signed by the accused to secure his or her presence at the trial. This obligation means that the accused may lose money by not properly appearing for the trial. Often referred to simply as bond</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAIL BONDSMAN</name>
<meaning>A person who is the liable party in paying the bond for the defendant's release from jail</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAIL FORFEITURE</name>
<meaning>Bail that is kept by the court as a result of not following a court order</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAIL REVIEW</name>
<meaning>A hearing established to re-evaluate the bail amount that was originally set for the accused</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAILIFF</name>
<meaning>A court officer who has charge of a court session in the matter of keeping order and has custody of the jury</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BANKRUPT</name>
<meaning>The state or condition of a person who is unable to pay his or her debts as they are or become due</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BANKRUPTCY</name>
<meaning>Refers to statutes and judicial proceedings involving persons or businesses that cannot pay their debts and seek the assistance of the court in getting a fresh start. Under the protection of the bankruptcy court, debtors may be released from or “discharged” from their debts, perhaps by paying a portion of each debt. Bankruptcy judges preside over these proceedings. The person with the debts is called the debtor and the people or companies to whom the debtor owes money to are called creditors</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAR</name>
<meaning>1. Historically, the partition separating the general public from the space occupied by the judges, lawyers, and other participants in a trial. 2. More commonly, the term means the whole body of lawyers</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BAR EXAMINATION</name>
<meaning>A state examination taken by prospective lawyers in order to be admitted and licensed to practice law</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BATTERED CHILD SYNDROME (B.C.S.)</name>
<meaning>Physical condition of a child indicating that external or internal injuries result from acts committed by a parent or custodian</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BATTERY</name>
<meaning>An offensive touching or use of force on a person without the person's consent</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BATTERY, SPOUSAL</name>
<meaning>- An offensive touching or use of force on one's spouse without the spouse's consent. See BATTERY</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BENCH</name>
<meaning>The seat occupied by judges in courts</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BENCH CONFERENCE</name>
<meaning>A meeting either on or off the record at the judge's bench between the judge, counsel, and sometimes the defendant, out of the hearing of the jury</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BENCH TRIAL</name>
<meaning>Trial without a jury in which a judge decides the facts</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BENCH WARRANT</name>
<meaning>An order issued by a judge for the arrest of a person</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BENEFICIARY</name>
<meaning>Someone named to receive property or benefits in a will. In a trust, a person who is to receive benefits from the trust</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BEQUEATH</name>
<meaning>To give a gift to someone through a will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BEQUESTS</name>
<meaning>Gifts made in a will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BEST EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Primary evidence; the best evidence available. Evidence short of this is “secondary.” That is, an original letter is “best evidence,” and a photocopy is “secondary evidence.”</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BEYOND A REASONABLE DOUBT</name>
<meaning>The standard in a criminal case requiring that the jury be satisfied to a moral certainty that every element of a crime has been proven by the prosecution. This standard of proof does not require that the state establish absolute certainty by eliminating all doubt, but it does require that the evidence be so conclusive that all reasonable doubts are removed from the mind of the ordinary person</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BIAS</name>
<meaning>Inclination, bent, a pre-conceived opinion or a predisposition to decide a cause or an issue a certain way</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BIFURCATE</name>
<meaning>To try issues separately, such as guilt and criminal responsibility in a criminal proceeding or liability and damages in a civil action</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BILL OF PARTICULARS</name>
<meaning>A statement of the details of the charge made against the defendant</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BIND OVER</name>
<meaning>To hold a person for trial on bond (bail) or in jail. If the judicial official conducting a hearing finds probable cause to believe the accused committed a crime, the official will bind over the accused, normally by setting bail for the accused's appearance at trial</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BODY ATTACHMENT</name>
<meaning>A written order issued by a court directing a sheriff or peace officer to take custody of and bring before the court: 1) A witness who fails to comply with a subpoena, 2) a party who fails to comply with a court order in a civil action, or 3) a material witness in a criminal case</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BOND</name>
<meaning>A certificate or evidence of a debt. Often used interchangeably with bail</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BOOKING</name>
<meaning>The process of photographing, fingerprinting, and recording identifying data of a suspect. This process follows the arrest</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BOOKING NUMBER</name>
<meaning>The number assigned to the criminal record that corresponds to the person's arrest</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BOOKMAKING</name>
<meaning>The act of collecting the bets of others or making odds on future gambling events</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BRANDISHING A WEAPON</name>
<meaning>The act of showing a weapon to another person, typically the police or the victim</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name> BREACH</name>
<meaning>The breaking or violating of a law, right, obligation, or duty either by doing an act or failing to do an act</meaning>
	</w>

<w>
      		<name>BREAKING AND ENTERING</name>
<meaning> Breaking and entering a dwelling of another in nighttime with intent to commit a felony therein</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BREATHALYZER TEST</name>
<meaning>Test to determine content of alcohol in one arrested for operating a motor vehicle while under the influence of liquor by analyzing a breath sample</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BRIBE</name>
<meaning> A gift, not necessarily of monetary value, given to influence the conduct of the receiver</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BRIEF</name>
<meaning>A written statement prepared by the counsel arguing a case in court. It contains a summary of the facts of a case, the pertinent laws, and an argument of how the law applies to the facts supporting counsel's position</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BURDEN OF PROOF</name>
<meaning>The obligation of a party to establish by evidence a requisite degree of belief concerning a fact in the mind of the trier of fact or the court</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>BURGLARY</name>
<meaning>The act of entering or remaining illegally in a movable or immovable structure, vehicle or dwelling with intent to commit a felony</meaning>
	</w>
</Bwords>

</root>
