<root>
<Dwords>
<w>
<name>DAMAGES</name>
<meaning>Money awarded by a court to a person injured by the unlawful act or negligence of another person</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEATH PENALTY</name>
<meaning>State-imposed death as punishment for a serious crime. Capital punishment</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEATH ROW</name>
<meaning>The area of a state or federal prison where criminals who are sentenced to death are confined until their sentence is commuted or carried out</meaning>
	</w>
 <w>
      		<name>DECISION</name>
<meaning>The judgment reached or given by a court of law</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DECLARATORY JUDGMENT</name>
<meaning>A judgment of the court that explains what the existing law is or expresses the opinion of the court without the need for enforcement</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DECREE</name>
<meaning>An order of the court. A final decree is one that fully and finally disposes of the litigation. An interlocutory decree is a preliminary order that often disposes of only part of a lawsuit</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFAMATION</name>
<meaning>That which tends to injure a person's reputation. Libel is published defamation, whereas slander is spoken</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFAULT</name>
<meaning>A failure to respond to a lawsuit within the specified time</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFAULT-JUDGMENT</name>
<meaning>A judgment entered against a party who fails to appear in court, respond to the charges, or does not comply with an order, especially an order to provide or permit discovery</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFENDANT</name>
<meaning> 1. In a criminal case, the person accused of the crime. 2. In a civil case, the person being sued </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFENSE</name>
<meaning>1. Defendant's statement of a reason why the plaintiff or prosecutor has no valid case against defendant, especially a defendant's answer, denial, or plea. 2. Defendant's method and strategy in opposing the plaintiff or the prosecution. 3. One or more defendants in a trial</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEFENSE ATTORNEY</name>
<meaning>An attorney who represents a person accused of committing a crime</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DELIBERATE</name>
<meaning>1. To discuss, ponder or reflect upon before reaching a decision. A judge will usually deliberate before announcing a judgment. 2. Intentional, characterized by consideration and awareness</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DELIBERATION</name>
<meaning>The jury's decision-making process after hearing the evidence and closing arguments and being given the court's instructions</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DELINQUENCY, JUVENILE</name>
<meaning>Antisocial behavior by a minor; especially behavior that would be criminally punishable if the actor were an adult, but instead is usually punished by special laws pertaining only to minors</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEMURRER</name>
<meaning>A motion to dismiss a civil case because of the legal insufficiency of a complaint</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEPENDENT CHILD</name>
<meaning>A child who is homeless or without proper care through no fault of the parent, guardian, or custodian</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEPORTATION</name>
<meaning>The act of removing a person to another country. Order issued by an immigration judge, expelling an alien from the United States. A deportation has certain consequences regarding the number of years within which a deportee may not legally immigrate. There are also criminal consequences for reentry within a prescribed time period</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEPOSITION</name>
<meaning>A pretrial discovery device by which one party questions the other party or a witness for the other party. It usually takes place in the office of one of the lawyers, in the presence of a court reporter, who transcribes what is said. Questions are asked and answered orally as if in court, with opportunity given to the adversary to cross-examine. Occasionally, the questions are submitted in writing and answered orally</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DEPRIVATION OF CUSTODY</name>
<meaning>The court transfer of legal custody of a person from parents or legal guardian to another person, agency, or institution. It may be temporary or permanent</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ASSISTANT STATE'S ATTORNEY </name>
<meaning>An assistant lawyer to the state's attorney</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>STATE'S ATTORNEY</name>
<meaning>A lawyer elected to represent the state in criminal cases in his or her respective juicial circuit. See PROSECUTOR</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DESCENT AND DISTRIBUTION STATUTES</name>
<meaning>State laws that provide for the distribution of estate property of a person who dies without a will. Same as intestacy laws</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DETENTION</name>
<meaning>The act or fact of holding a person in custody; confinement or compulsory delay</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DETENTION HEARING</name>
<meaning>In juvenile court, a judicial hearing, usually held after the filing of a petition, to determine interim custody of a minor pending a judgment</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DIRECT EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Proof of facts by witnesses who saw acts done or heard words spoken</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DIRECT EXAMINATION</name>
<meaning>The first questioning of witnesses by the party on whose behalf they are called</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DIRECTED VERDICT</name>
<meaning>Now called Judgment as a Matter of Law. An instruction by the judge to the jury to return a specific verdict</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISBARMENT</name>
<meaning>Form of discipline of a lawyer resulting in the loss (often permanently) of that lawyer's right to practice law. It differs from censure (an official reprimand or condemnation) and from suspension (a temporary loss of the right to practice law)</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISCLAIM</name>
<meaning>To refuse a gift made in a will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISCOVERY</name>
<meaning>The procedure by which one or both parties disclose evidence which will be used at trial. The specific tools of discovery include depositions, interrogatories and motions for the production of documents</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISMISS</name>
<meaning>To terminate legal action involving outstanding charges against a defendant in a criminal case</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISMISSAL WITH PREJUDICE</name>
<meaning>The dismissal of a case, by which the same cause of action cannot be brought against the defendant again at a later date</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISMISSAL WITHOUT PREJUDICE</name>
<meaning>The dismissal of a case without preventing the plaintiff from bringing the same cause of action against the defendant in the future</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISORDERLY CONDUCT</name>
<meaning>Any behavior, contrary to law, which disturbs the public peace or decorum, scandalizes the community, or shocks the public sense of morality</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISPOSITION</name>
<meaning>A final settlement or determination. The court decision terminating proceedings in a case before judgment is reached, or the final judgment</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISSENT</name>
<meaning>To disagree. An appellate court opinion setting forth the minority view and outlining the disagreement of one or more judges with the decision of the majority</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISSOLUTION</name>
<meaning>The act of bringing to an end; termination. The dissolution of a marriage or other relationship</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISTRICT ATTORNEY</name>
<meaning>A lawyer appointed or elected to represent the state in criminal cases in his or her respective judicial districts. See PROSECUTOR</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DISTURBING THE PEACE</name>
<meaning>Conduct which tends to annoy all citizens, including unnecessary and distracting noisemaking</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DIVERSION</name>
<meaning>1. The process of removing some minor criminal traffic, or juvenile cases from the full judicial process, on the condition that the accused undergo some sort of rehabilitation or make restitution for damages. 2. Unauthorized use of funds</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DIVORCE</name>
<meaning>Legal dissolution of a marriage by a court. Also termed dissolution of marriage</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DOCKET</name>
<meaning>A list of cases to be heard by a court, or a log containing brief entries of court proceedings</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DOCKET NUMBER</name>
<meaning>The designation assigned to each case filed in a particular court. Also called a case number</meaning>
	</w>

 <w>
      		<name>DOMESTIC VIOLENCE</name>
<meaning>An assault committed by one member of a household against another</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DOMICILE</name>
<meaning>The place where a person has his or her permanent legal home. A person may have several residences, but only one domicile</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DOUBLE JEOPARDY</name>
<meaning>The constitutional prohibition under the Fifth Amendment against a person being put on trial more than once for the same offense</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE</name>
<meaning>The unlawful operation of a motor vehicle while under the influence of drugs or alcohol</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DRUNK DRIVING</name>
<meaning>The operation of a vehicle in an impaired state after consuming alcohol that when tested is above the state's legal alcohol limit</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>DUE PROCESS OF LAW</name>
<meaning>The right of all persons to receive the guarantees and safeguards of the law and the judicial process. It includes such constitutional requirements as adequate notice, assistance of counsel, the right to remain silent, the right to a speedy and public trial, the right to an impartial jury, and the right to confront and secure witnesses</meaning>
	</w>
</Dwords>

</root>
