<root>
<Ewords>
<w>
      		<name>ELEMENTS OF A CRIME</name>
<meaning>Specific factors that define a crime which the prosecution must prove beyond a reasonable doubt in order to obtain a conviction. The elements that must be proven are 1) that a crime has actually occurred, 2) the accused intended the crime to happen, and 3) a timely relationship between the first two factors sufficient to support causation</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EMBEZZLE</name>
<meaning>To willfully take or convert to one's own use, another's money or property, which the wrongdoer initially acquired lawfully, because of some office, employment, or some position of trust</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EMINENT DOMAIN</name>
<meaning>The power of the government to take private property for public use through condemnation</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EN BANC</name>
<meaning>All the judges of a court sitting together. Appellate courts can consist of a dozen or more judges, but often they hear cases in panels of three judges. If a case is heard or reheard by the full court, it is heard en banc</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ENHANCE</name>
<meaning>To make greater in value, to increase</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ENJOINING</name>
<meaning>An order by the court telling a person to stop performing a specific act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ENTER A GUILTY PLEA</name>
<meaning>The formal statement before the court that the accused admits committing the criminal act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ENTRAPMENT</name>
<meaning>A defense to criminal charges alleging that agents of the government induced a person to commit a crime he or she otherwise would not have committed</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EQUAL PROTECTION</name>
<meaning>The guarantee in the Fourteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution that all persons be treated equally by the law</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EQUITABLE ACTION</name>
<meaning>An action which may be brought for the purpose of restraining the threatened infliction of wrongs or injuries, and the prevention of threatened illegal action</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EQUITY</name>
<meaning>Generally, justice or fairness. Historically, equity refers to a separate body of law developed in England in reaction to the inability of the common-law courts, in their strict adherence to rigid writs and forms of action, to consider or provide a remedy for every injury. The king therefore established the court of chancery to do justice between parties in cases where the common law would give inadequate redress. The principle of this system of law is that equity will find a way to achieve a lawful result when legal procedure is inadequate. Equity and law courts are now merged in most jurisdictions</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ESCHEAT (ES-CHET)</name>
<meaning>The process by which a deceased person's property goes to the state if no heir can be found</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ESCROW</name>
<meaning>Money or a written instrument such as a deed that, by agreement between two parties, is held by a neutral third party (held in escrow) until all conditions of the agreement are met</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ESTATE</name>
<meaning>An estate consists of personal property (car, household items, and other tangible items), real property, and intangible property, such as stock certificates and bank accounts, owned in the individual name of a person at the time of the person's death. It does not include life insurance proceeds (unless the estate was made the beneficiary) or other assets that pass outside the estate (like joint tenancy assets)</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ESTATE TAX</name>
<meaning>Generally, a tax on the privilege of transferring property to others after a person's death. In addition to federal estate taxes, many states have their own estate taxes</meaning>
	</w>


<w>
      		<name>ESTOPPEL</name>
<meaning>A person's own act, or acceptance of facts, which preclude his or her later making claims to the contrary</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EVICTION</name>
<meaning>Recovery of land or rental property from another by legal process</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Information presented in testimony or in documents that is used to persuade the fact finder (judge or jury) to decide the case for one side or the other</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EVIDENCE, CIRCUMSTANTIAL</name>
<meaning>Inferences drawn from proven facts</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EVIDENCE, DIRECT</name>
<meaning>Evidence in form of witness testimony, who actually saw, heard, or touched the subject of question</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EVIDENCE, EVANESCENT</name>
<meaning>Evidence which can disappear relatively quickly, such as the amount of alcohol in a person's blood</meaning>
	</w>

<w>
      		<name>EXAMINATION, DIRECT</name>
<meaning>The first examination of a witness by the counsel who called the witness to testify</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXAMINATION, RECROSS</name>
<meaning>A second examination of a witness by the opposing counsel after the second examination (or redirect examination) by the counsel who called the witness to testify is completed</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXAMINATION, REDIRECT</name>
<meaning>A second examination of a witness by the counsel who called the witness to testify. This examination is usually focused on certain matters that were discussed by the opposing counsel's examination</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXCEPTIONS</name>
<meaning>Declarations by either side in a civil or criminal case reserving the right to appeal a judge's ruling upon a motion. Also, in regulatory cases, objections by either side to points made by the other side or to rulings by the agency or one of its hearing officers</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXCLUSION OF WITNESSES</name>
<meaning>An order of the court requiring all witnesses to remain outside the courtroom until each is called to testify, except the plaintiff or defendant. The witnesses are ordered not to discuss their testimony with each other and may be held in contempt if they violate the order</meaning>
	</w>


<w>
      		<name>EXCLUSIONARY RULE</name>
<meaning>The rule preventing illegally obtained evidence to be used in any trial</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXCLUSIVE JURISDICTION</name>
<meaning>The matter can only be filed in one court</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXCULPATORY EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Evidence which tends to indicate that a defendant did not commit the alleged crime</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXECUTE</name>
<meaning>To complete the legal requirements (such as signing before witnesses) that make a will valid. Also, to execute a judgment or decree means to put the final judgment of the court into effect</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXECUTOR</name>
<meaning>A personal representative, named in a will, who administers an estate</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXHIBIT</name>
<meaning>A document or other item introduced as evidence during a trial or hearing</meaning>
	</w>

<w>
      		<name>EXHIBIT, PEOPLE'S</name>
<meaning>Exhibit and/or evidence that is offered by the prosecution</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXONERATE</name>
<meaning>Removal of a charge, responsibility or duty</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXPERT TESTIMONY</name>
<meaning>Testimony given in relation to some scientific, technical, or professional matter by experts, i.e., person qualified to speak authoritatively by reason of their special training, skill, or familiarity with the subject</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXPUNGEMENT</name>
<meaning>Official and formal erasure of a record or partial contents of a record</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXTENUATING CIRCUMSTANCES</name>
<meaning>Circumstances which render a crime less aggravated, heinous, or reprehensible than it would otherwise be</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXTORTION</name>
<meaning>The act of obtaining the property of another person through wrongful use of actual or threatened force, violence, or fear</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXTRADITION</name>
<meaning>The process by which one state or country surrenders to another state, a person accused or convicted of a crime in the other state</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>EXTRAORDINARY WRIT</name>
<meaning>A writ, often issued by an appellate court, making available remedies not regularly within the powers of lower courts. They include writs of habeas corpus, mandamus, prohibition and quo warranto</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>EYE WITNESS</name>
<meaning>One who saw the act, fact, or transaction to which he or she testifies</meaning>
	</w>
</Ewords>
</root>
