<root>
<Fwords>
<w>
     		<name>FAILURE TO APPEAR</name>
<meaning>The act of not appearing in court after being presented with a subpoena or summons</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FAILURE TO COMPLY</name>
<meaning>The act of not following an order that is directed by the court</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name> FAIR HEARING</name>
<meaning>A hearing in which certain rights are respected such as the right to present evidence, to cross examine and to have findings supported by evidence</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name> FALSE ARREST</name>
<meaning>Any unlawful physical restraint of another's personal liberty, whether or not carried out by a peace officer</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name> FALSE IMPRISONMENT</name>
<meaning>The unlawful restraint by one person of another person's physical liberty</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FALSE PRETENSES</name>
<meaning>Representation of some fact or circumstance which is not true and is calculated to mislead, whereby a person obtains another's money or goods</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FAMILY ALLOWANCE</name>
<meaning>A small amount of money set aside from the estate of the deceased. Its purpose is to provide for the surviving family members during the administration of the estate</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FELONY</name>
<meaning>A crime of a more serious nature than a misdemeanor, usually punishable by imprisonment in a penitentiary for more than a year and/or substantial fines</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FELONY MURDER</name>
<meaning>A murder committed during the commission of a felony such as robbery, burglary, or kidnapping</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIDELITY BOND</name>
<meaning>See SURETY BOND</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIDUCIARY</name>
<meaning>A person having a legal relationship of trust and confidence to another and having a duty to act primarily for the others benefit, e.g., a guardian, trustee, or executor</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIELD SOBRIETY TEST</name>
<meaning>A method of determining whether a person is intoxicated using a motor skills test which is administered by testing the driver's speaking ability and/or physical coordination</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIFTH AMENDMENT</name>
<meaning>Among other rights, the Fifth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution guarantees that a person cannot be compelled to present self-incriminating testimony in a criminal proceeding</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FILE</name>
<meaning>To place a paper in the official custody of the clerk of court to enter into the files or records of a case</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIND GUILTY</name>
<meaning>For the judge or jury to determine and declare the guilt of the defendant</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FINDING</name>
<meaning>Formal conclusion by a judge or jury on issues of fact</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FINE</name>
<meaning>A fine is money paid usually to superior authority, usually governmental authority, as a punishment for a crime or other offence. The amount of a fine can be determined case by case.</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FINGERPRINT</name>
<meaning>The distinctive pattern of lines on human fingertips that are used as a method of identification in criminal cases</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIREARM</name>
<meaning>A weapon which acts by force of gunpowder, such as a rifle, shotgun or revolver</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FIRST APPEARANCE</name>
<meaning>The initial appearance of an arrested person before a judge to determine whether there is probable cause for his or her arrest. Generally the person comes before a judge within hours of the arrest, and are informed of the charges against him or her and of his or her rights to a preliminary hearing, to counsel,and to bail. No plea is asked for at this state. Also called initial appearance</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FORCIBLE ENTRY AND DETAINER</name>
<meaning>Ordinarily refers to a summary proceeding for restoring possession of land to one who has been wrongfully deprived of possession</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FORECLOSURE</name>
<meaning>Procedure by which mortgaged property is sold on default of the mortgagor in satisfaction of mortgage debt</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FORFEIT</name>
<meaning>To lose, or lose the right to</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FORFEITURE</name>
<meaning>The loss of money or property resulting from failure to meet a legal obligation or from the illegal nature or use of the money or property</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FORGERY</name>
<meaning>The act of claiming one's own writing to be that of another</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FOSTER CARE</name>
<meaning>A weapon which acts by force of gunpowder, such as a rifle, shotgun or revolver</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FOUNDATION</name>
<meaning>In a trial, a foundation must be laid to establish the basis for the admissibility of certain types of evidence. For example, an expert witnesses's qualifications must be shown before expert testimony will be admissible</meaning>
	</w>

<w>
     		<name>FOURTH AMENDMENT</name>
<meaning>Among other matters, the 14th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution prohibits states from depriving any person of life, liberty, or property without adequate due process</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>FRAUD</name>
<meaning>Intentional, unlawful deception to deprive another person of property or to injure that person in some other way</meaning>
	</w>
</Fwords>
</root>
