<root>
<Gwords>
<w>
     		<name>GAMBLING</name>
<meaning>The act of staking money, or other thing of value, on an uncertain event or outcome</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GARNISH</name>
<meaning>To withhold a debtor's money, and turn it over to another in order to pay a debt. Typically, the one withholding the money is the debtor's employer</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GARNISHMENT</name>
<meaning>A legal proceeding in which a debtor's money, in the possession of another (the garnishee), is applied to the debts of the debtor, such as when an employer garnishes a debtor's wages</meaning>
	</w>


<w>
     		<name>GENERAL ASSIGNMENT</name>
<meaning>The voluntary transfer, by a debtor, of all property to a trustee for the benefit of all of his or her creditors</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GENERAL JURISDICTION</name>
<meaning>Refers to courts that have no limit on the types of criminal and civil cases they may hear</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GLUE SNIFFING</name>
<meaning>The act of inhaling glue in order "to get high"</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GOOD CAUSE</name>
<meaning>Substantial reason, one that affords a legal excuse</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GOOD FAITH</name>
<meaning>An honest belief, the absence of malice, and the absence of design to defraud</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GOOD TIME</name>
<meaning>A reduction in sentenced time in prison as a reward for good behavior. It usually is one-third to one-half off the maximum sentence</meaning>
	</w>


<w>
     		<name>GRAND JURY</name>
<meaning>Jury of inquiry. The jury which determines which charges, if any, are to be brought against a defendant</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GRAND THEFT</name>
<meaning>Taking and carrying away the personal property of another person of a value in excess of an amount set by law with the intent to deprive the owner or possessor of it permanently</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GRANTOR OR SETTLOR</name>
<meaning>The person who sets up a trust</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GROUNDS</name>
<meaning>A foundation or basis; points relied on</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GUARDIAN</name>
<meaning>A person appointed by will or by law to assume responsibility for incompetent adults or minor children. If a parent dies, this will usually be the other parent. If both die, it probably will be a close relative</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GUARDIANSHIP</name>
<meaning>Legal right given to a person to be responsible for the food, housing, health care, and other necessities of a person deemed incapable of providing these necessities for himself or herself, usually an incompetent adult or minor child</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
     		<name>GUILTY</name>
<meaning>Responsible for a delinquency, crime, or other offense; not innocent</meaning>
	</w>

</Gwords>


</root>

