<root>
   <Iwords>
    <w>
        <name>ILLEGAL </name>
        <meaning>Against, or not authorized by law; unlawful. IMMUNITY - Grant by the court which assures someone will not face prosecution in return for providing evidence in a criminal proceeding </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>IMPANEL</name>
        <meaning>To seat a jury. When voir dire is finished and both sides have exercised their challenges, the jury is impaneled. The jurors are sworn in and the trial is ready to proceed </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name> IMPEACHMENT OF WITNESS </name>
        <meaning> To call into question the truthfulness of a witness </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>IMPLIED CONTRACT </name>
        <meaning> A contract in which the promise made by the obligor is not expressed, but inferred by one's conduct or implied in law </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INADMISSIBLE </name>
        <meaning> That which, under the rules of evidence, cannot be admitted as evidence in a trial or hearing </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INCAPACITY</name>
        <meaning>The lack of power or the legal ability to act </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INCARCERATE</name>
        <meaning>To confine in jail </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INCEST</name>
        <meaning> Sexual intercourse between persons so closely related that marriage between them would be unlawful </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INCOMPETENCY</name>
        <meaning> Lack of capacity to understand the nature and object of the proceedings, to consult with counsel, and to assist in preparing a defense </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INCRIMINATE</name>
        <meaning> To make it appear that one is guilty of a crime </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDECENT EXPOSURE</name>
        <meaning> Exposure to sight of the private parts of the body in a lewd or indecent manner in a public place </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDEMNIFY</name>
        <meaning> The term pertains to liability for loss shifted from one person held legally responsible to another </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDEPENDENT EXECUTOR</name>
        <meaning>A special kind of executor, permitted by the laws of certain states, who performs the duties of an executor without intervention by the court</meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDETERMINATE SENTENCE</name>
        <meaning>A sentence of imprisonment to a specified minimum and maximum period of time, specifically authorized by statute, subject to termination by a parole board or other authorized agency after the prisoner has served the minimum term</meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDICTMENT</name>
        <meaning> A formal written accusation, issued by a grand jury, charging a party with a crime </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INDIGENT</name>
        <meaning> Needy and poor. A defendant who can demonstrate his or her indigence to the court may be assigned a court- appointed attorney at public expense </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INFORMANT</name>
        <meaning> An undisclosed person who confidentially discloses material information of a crime to the police, which is usually done in exchange for a reward or special treatment </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INFORMATION </name>
        <meaning> A formal written document filed by the prosecutor detailing the criminal charges against the defendant. An alternative to an indictment, it serves to bring a defendant to trial </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INFRACTION </name>
        <meaning> A violation of law, not punishable by imprisonment. Minor traffic offenses are generally considered infractions </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INHERITANCE TAX </name>
        <meaning> A state tax on property that an heir or beneficiary under a will receives from a deceased person's estate. The heir or beneficiary pays this tax </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INITIAL APPEARANCE </name>
        <meaning>In criminal law, the hearing at which a judge determines whether there is sufficient evidence against a person charged with a crime to hold him or her for trial. The Constitution bans secret accusations, so initial appearances are public unless the defendant asks otherwise; the accused must be present, though he or she usually does not offer evidence. Also called first appearance</meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INJUNCTION </name>
        <meaning> Writ or order by a court prohibiting a specific action from being carried out by a person or group </meaning>
	</w>

       <w>
           <name>INMATE </name>
        <meaning> A person confined to a prison, penitentiary, or jail </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INNOCENT UNTIL PROVEN GUILTY </name>
        <meaning>A belief in the American legal system which states that all people accused of a criminal act are considered not to have committed the crime until the evidence leaves no doubt in the mind of the court or the jury that the accused did or did not commit the crime</meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INSANITY PLEA</name>
        <meaning> A claim by a defendant that he or she lacks the soundness of mind required by law to accept responsibility for a criminal act </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INSTRUCTIONS</name>
        <meaning> Judge's explanation to the jury before it begins deliberations of the questions it must answer and the applicable law governing the case. Also called charge </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTANGIBLE ASSETS</name>
        <meaning> Nonphysical items such as stock certificates, bonds, bank accounts, and pension benefits that have value and must be taken into account in estate planning </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTENT</name>
        <meaning> The purpose to use a particular means to bring about a certain result </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTERLOCUTORY</name>
        <meaning> Provisional; not final. An interlocutory order or an interlocutory appeal concerns only a part of the issues raised in a lawsuit. Compare to decree </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTERROGATORIES</name>
        <meaning> Written questions asked by one party in a lawsuit for which the opposing party must provide written answers </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTERVENTION</name>
        <meaning>An action by which a third person who may be affected by a lawsuit is permitted to become a party to the suit. Differs from the process of becoming an amicus curiae </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTESTACY LAWS</name>
        <meaning>See DESCENT AND DISTRIBUTION STATUTES </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTESTATE</name>
        <meaning> Dying without a will </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INTESTATE SUCCESSION </name>
        <meaning>The process by which the property of a person who has died without a will passes on to others according to the state's descent and distribution statutes. If someone dies without a will, and the court uses the state’s interstate succession laws, an heir who receives some of the deceased's property is an intestate heir</meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>INVESTIGATION </name>
        <meaning> A legal inquiry to discover and collect facts concerning a certain matter </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>IRRELEVANT </name>
        <meaning> Evidence not sufficiently related to the matter in issue </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>IRREVOCABLE TRUST </name>
        <meaning> A trust that, once set up, the grantor may not revoke </meaning>
	</w>

    <w>
        <name>ISSUE</name>
        <meaning>1) The disputed point in a disagreement between parties in a lawsuit.
            2) To send out officially, as in to issue an order.
        </meaning>
	</w>

    </Iwords>
</root>