<root>
<Owords>
	<w>
      		<name>OATH</name>
      		<meaning>Written or oral pledge by a witness to speak the truth</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OBJECT</name>
<meaning>To protest to the court against an act or omission by the opposing party</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OBJECTION</name>
      		<meaning>A protest to the court against an act or omission by the opposing party</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OBJECTION OVERRULED</name>
<meaning>A ruling by the court against the party making the objection</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OBJECTION SUSTAINED</name>
      		<meaning>A ruling by the court in favor of the party making the objection</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OF COUNSEL</name>
<meaning>A phrase commonly applied to counsel employed to assist in the preparation or management of the case, or its presentation on appeal, but who is not the principal attorney for the party</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OFFENDER</name>
      		<meaning>One who commits a crime, such as a felony, misdemeanor, or other punishable unlawful act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OFFENSE</name>
<meaning>A crime, such as a felony, misdemeanor, or other punishable unlawful act</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OFFER OF PROOF</name>
      		<meaning>Presentation of evidence to the court (out of the hearing of the jury) for the court's decision of whether the evidence is admissible</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ON A PERSON'S OWN RECOGNIZANCE</name>
<meaning>Release of a person from custody without the payment of any bail or posting of bond, upon the promise to return to court</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OPENING ARGUMENT</name>
      		<meaning>The initial statement made by attorneys for each side, outlining the facts each intends to establish during the trial</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OPENING STATEMENT</name>
<meaning> The initial statement made by attorneys for each side, outlining the facts each intends to establish during the trial </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OPINION</name>
      		<meaning>A judge's written explanation of a decision of the court or of a majority of judges. A dissenting opinion disagrees with the majority opinion because of the 				reasoning and/or the principles of law on which the decision is based. A concurring 			opinion agrees with the decision of the court but offers further comment. A per curiam 			opinion is an unsigned opinion “of the court.”</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OPINION EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Witnesses are normally required to confine their testimony to statements of fact and are not allowed to give their opinions in court.  However, if a witness is qualified as an expert in a particular field, he or she may be allowed to state an opinion as an expert based on certain facts</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>ORAL ARGUMENT</name>
      		<meaning>An opportunity for lawyers to summarize their position before the court and also to answer the judges' questions</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ORDER TO SHOW CAUSE</name>
<meaning>Court order requiring to appear and show cause why the court should not take a particular course of action.  If the party fails to appear or to give sufficient reasons why the court should take no action, the court will take the action.  In criminal cases, the defendant must show why probation should not be revoked</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>ORDER, COURT</name>
      		<meaning>A written or verbal command from a court directing or forbidding an action</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>ORDINANCE</name>
<meaning>An act of legislation of a local governing body such as a city, town or county</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>ORIGINAL JURISDICTION</name>
      		<meaning>A protest to the court against an act or omission by the opposing party</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OVERRULE</name>
<meaning>A judge's decision not to allow an objection. A decision by a higher court finding that a lower court decision was wrong</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>OVERRULED</name>
      		<meaning> A judge's decision not to allow an objection. A decision by a higher court finding that a lower court decision was wrong </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>OVERT ACT</name>
<meaning>An open act showing the intent to commit a crime</meaning>
	</w>
    </Owords>
</root>
