<root>
<Pwords>
	<w>
      		<name>PANDERING</name>
      		<meaning>Pimping. Arranging for acts of prostitution</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PARALEGAL</name>
<meaning>A person with legal skills, but who is not an attorney, and who works under the supervision of a lawyer or who is otherwise authorized by law to use those legal skills</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PARDON</name>
      		<meaning>A form of executive clemency preventing criminal prosecution or removing 			or extinguishing a criminal conviction</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PAROLE</name>
<meaning>Supervised release of a prisoner before the expiration of his or her sentence</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PAROLE EVIDENCE</name>
      		<meaning>Oral or verbal evidence rather than written.  The Parole Evidence Rule limits 			the admissibility of parole evidence which would directly contradict the clear meaning 			of terms of a written contract</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PARTY</name>
<meaning> A person, business, or government agency actively involved in the prosecution or defense of a legal proceeding </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PATENT</name>
      		<meaning>A government grant giving an inventor the exclusive right to make or sell his 			or her invention for a term of years</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PATERNITY</name>
<meaning>Fatherhood</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PENALTY</name>
      		<meaning>Punishment, civil or criminal, generally referring to payment of money 			</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PENDING</name>
<meaning>Begun, but not yet completed.  Thus, an action is pending from its inception until the rendition of its final judgment</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PENITENTIARY</name>
      		<meaning>A prison or place of confinement where convicted felons are sent to serve			out the term of their sentence</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PEOPLE (PROSECUTION)</name>
<meaning>The state, as in the People of the State of Florida</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PEREMPTORY CHALLENGE</name>
      		<meaning>The right to challenge a juror without assigning a reason for the challenge			 </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PERJURY</name>
<meaning>A false statement given while under oath or in a sworn affidavit</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PERMANENT INJUNCTION</name>
      		<meaning> A court order requiring that some action be taken, or that some party refrain 		from taking action. It differs from forms of temporary relief, such as a temporary 			restraining order or preliminary injunction </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PERMANENT RESIDENT</name>
<meaning> One who lives in a location for a period of time and denotes it as their official address or residence </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PERSON IN NEED OF SUPERVISION</name>
      		<meaning> Juvenile found to have committed a status offense rather than a crime that			would provide a basis for a finding of delinquency. Typical status offenses are habitual 			truancy, violating a curfew, or running away from home. These are not crimes, but they 			might be enough to place a child under supervision. In different states, status offenders 			might be called children in need of supervision or minors in need of supervision 				</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PERSONAL PROPERTY</name>
<meaning>Tangible physical property (such as cars, clothing, furniture, and jewelry) and intangible personal property. This does not include real property such as land or rights in land</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PERSONAL RECOGNIZANCE</name>
      		<meaning> Pre-trial release based on the person's own promise that he or she will show 		up for trial (no bond required).  Also referred to as release on own recognizance or ROR 			</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PERSONAL REPRESENTATIVE</name>
<meaning>The person who administers an estate. If named in a will, that person's title is an executor. If there is no valid will, that person's title is an administrator</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PETIT JURY</name>
      		<meaning>The ordinary jury of twelve (or fewer) persons for the trial of a civil or 			criminal case.  So called to distinguish it from the grand jury</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PETITION</name>
<meaning>A formal, written application to the court requesting judicial action on some matter</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PETITIONER</name>
<meaning>The person filing an action in a court of original jurisdiction. Also, the person who appeals the judgment of a lower court. The opposing party is called the respondent</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PETTY OFFENSE</name>
      		<meaning>A misdemeanor or minor offense or comparatively insignificatn criminal 			act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PETTY THEFT</name>
<meaning>The act of taking and carrying away the personal property of another of a value less than $300 with the intent to deprive the owner or possessor of it permanently</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PIMP</name>
      		<meaning>To obtain customers for a whore or prostitute. One who obtains customers 			for a whore or prostitute </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PLAINTIFF</name>
<meaning>A person who initiates a lawsuit against another. Also called the complainant</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PLEA</name>
      		<meaning>In a criminal proceeding, it is the defendant's declaration in open court that			he or she is guilty or not guilty. The defendant's answer to the charges made in the 			indictment or information</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PLEA BARGAIN</name>
<meaning>The process whereby the accused and the prosecutor in a criminal case work out a mutually satisfactory disposition of the case subject to court approval. Usually involves the defendant's pleading guilty to a lesser offense or to only one</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PLEADINGS</name>
      		<meaning>The written statements of fact and law filed by the parties to a lawsuit			</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>POLLING THE JURY</name>
<meaning>The act, after a jury verdict has been announced, of asking jurors individually whether they agree with the verdict</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>POLYGRAPH</name>
      		<meaning>Lie detector test and the apparatus for conducting the test</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>POSSESSION OF DRUGS</name>
<meaning>The presence of drugs on the accused for recreational use or for the purpose to sell</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>POST CONVICTION REFIEF PROCEEDING</name>
      		<meaning>A procedure by which a convicted defendant challenges the conviction 			and/or sentence on the basis of some alleged violation or error</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>POSTPONEMENT</name>
<meaning>To put off or delay a court hearing</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>POUR-OVER WILL</name>
<meaning>A will that leaves some or all estate assets to a trust established before the will-maker's death</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>POWER OF ATTORNEY</name>
      		<meaning>Formal authorization of a person to act in the interest of another 				person</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRECEDENT</name>
<meaning>A previously decided case that guides the decision of future cases</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRE-INJUNCTION</name>
<meaning>Court order requiring action or forbidding action until a decision can be made whether to issue a permanent injunction. It differs from a temporary restraining order</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PREJUDICE</name>
      		<meaning>A forejudgment, bias, a preconceived opinion</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PREJUDICIAL ERROR</name>
<meaning>Synonymous with reversible error; an error which warrants the appellate court in reversing the judgment before it</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PREJUDICIAL EVIDENCE</name>
      		<meaning>Evidence which might unfairly sway the judge or jury to one side or the 			other</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRELIMINARY EXAMINATION</name>
<meaning>The hearing available to a person charged with a felony to determine if there is enough evidence (probable cause) to hold him for trial</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRELIMINARY HEARING</name>
      		<meaning>Another term for arraignment</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRELIMINARY INJUNCTION</name>
<meaning>In civil cases when it is necessary to preserve the status quo prior to trial, the court may issue a preliminary injunction or temporary restraining order ordering a party to carry out a specified activity</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PREMEDITATION</name>
      		<meaning>The planning of a crime preceding the commission of the act, rather than 			committing the crime on the spur of the moment</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PREPONDERANCE OF THE EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Evidence which is of greater weight or more convincing than the evidence which is offered in opposition to it</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRE-SENTENCE REPORT</name>
      		<meaning>A report to the sentencing judge containing background information about 			the crime and the defendant to assist the judge in making his or her sentencing 				decision</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRESENTMENT</name>
<meaning>Declaration or document issued by a grand jury that either makes a neutral report or notes misdeeds by officials charged with specified public duties. It ordinarily does not include a formal charge of crime. A presentment differs from an indictment</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRESUMPTION</name>
      		<meaning>An inference of the truth or falsity of a proposition or fact, that stands until 			rebutted by evidence to the contrary</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name> PRESUMPTION OF INNOCENCE </name>
<meaning> A hallowed principle of criminal law that a person is innocent of a crime until proven guilty. The government has the burden of proving every element of a crime beyond a reasonable doubt and the defendant has no burden to prove his innocence </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRESUMPTION OF LAW</name>
      		<meaning>a rule of law that courts and judges shall draw a particular inference from a 			particular fact, or from particular evidence</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRETERMITTED CHILD</name>
<meaning>A child born or adopted after a will is executed, who is not provided for in the will</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRETERMITTED SPOUSE</name>
      		<meaning>A husband or wife of a deceased spouse married after a will is executed who 			is not provided for in the will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRE-TRIAL CONFERENCE</name>
<meaning>A meeting between the judge and the lawyers involved in a lawsuit to narrow the issues in the suit, agree on what will be presented at the trial, and make a final effort to settle the case without a trial</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRIORS</name>
      		<meaning>A slang term meaning previous conviction(s) of the accused</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRISON</name>
<meaning>A federal or state public building or other place for the confinement of persons. It is used as either a punishment imposed by the law or otherwise in the course of the administration of justice. Also known as penitentiary, penal institution, adult correctional institution, or jail</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRIVILEGE</name>
<meaning>A legal right, exemption or immunity granted to a person, company or class, that is beyond the common advantages of other citizens</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PRIVILEGED COMMUNICATIONS</name>
      		<meaning>Confidential communications to certain persons that are protected by law 			against any disclosure, including forced disclosure in legal proceedings. Communications 		between lawyer and client, physician and patient, psychotherapist and patient, priest,			minister, or rabbi and penitent are typically privileged</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PRIVITY</name>
<meaning>Mutual or successive relationships to the same right of property, or the same interest of one person with another which represents the same legal right</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROBABLE CAUSE</name>
<meaning>A reasonable belief that a crime has or is being committed; the basis for all lawful searches, seizures, and arrests</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROBATE</name>
      		<meaning>The court-supervised process by which a will is determined to be the 			will-maker's final statement regarding how the will-maker wants his or her 			property distributed. It also confirms the appointment of the personal 				representative of the estate. Probate also means the process by which assets 			are gathered; applied to pay debts, taxes, and expenses of administration; and 			distributed to those designated as beneficiaries in the will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROBATE COURT</name>
<meaning>The court with authority to supervise estate administration</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROBATE ESTATE</name>
      		<meaning>Estate property that may be disposed of by a will</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROBATION</name>
<meaning>A sentence imposed for the commission of a crime whereby a convicted criminal offender is released into the community, usually under conditions and under the supervision of a probation officer, instead of incarceration. A violation of probation can lead to its revocation and to imprisonment</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROBATION BEFORE JUDGMENT (PBJ)</name>
      		<meaning>Placing a convicted defendant on conditional probation, the successful 			completion of which will prevent entry of the underlying judgment of conviction. More 			commonly referred to in Florida as DEFERRED ADJUDICATION or DEFERRED 				JUDGMENT</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROBATION DEPARTMENT</name>
<meaning>The department that oversees the actions of probationers as well as the location of where probation officers work</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROBATION OFFICER</name>
      		<meaning>One who supervises a person placed on probation and is required to report 			the progress and to surrender the probationer if they violate the terms and conditions 			of the probation</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROCEDURAL LAW</name>
<meaning>The method, established normally by rules to be followed in a case; the formal steps in a judicial proceeding</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROFFER</name>
      		<meaning>An offer of proof as to what the evidence would be if a witness were called 			to testify or answer a question</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROOF</name>
<meaning>Any fact or evidence that leads to a judgment of the court</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROSECUTION</name>
      		<meaning>A proceeding instituted and carried on in order to determine the guilt or 			innocence of the accused</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROSECUTOR</name>
<meaning>A trial lawyer representing the government in a criminal case and the interests of the state in civil matters. In criminal cases, the prosecutor has the responsibility of deciding who and when to prosecute</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROSTITUTION</name>
<meaning>The performance or agreement to perform a sexual act for hire</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PROTECTIVE ORDER</name>
<meaning>A court order to protect a person from further harassment, service of process, or discovery</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PROXIMATE CAUSE</name>
      		<meaning>The act that caused an event to occur. A person generally is liable 			only if an injury was proximately caused by his or her action or by his or her 			failure to act when he or she had a duty to act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PUBLIC DEFENDER</name>
<meaning>An attorney appointed by a court or employed by a government agency whose work consists primarily of defending people who are unable to hire a lawyer due to economic reasons</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>PUNITIVE DAMAGES</name>
      		<meaning>Money awarded to an injured person, over and above the measurable value 			of the injury, in order to punish the person who hurt him</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>PURGE</name>
<meaning>To clean or clear, such as eliminating inactive records from court files; with respect to civil contempt, to cure the noncompliance that caused the contempt finding</meaning>
	</w>
    </Pwords>

</root>
