<root>
<Rwords>
	<w>
      		<name>RAP SHEET</name>
      		<meaning>A listing of all the criminal convictions against an individual</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RAPE</name>
<meaning>Unlawful intercourse with an individual without their consent</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RAPE, STATUTORY</name>
      		<meaning> Unlawful sexual intercourse with a person under the age of 18, regardless of whether they consent to the act</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RATIFICATION</name>
<meaning>The confirmation or adoption of a previous act done either by the party himself or by another</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REAL EVIDENCE</name>
      		<meaning>Evidence given to explain, repel, counteract, or disprove facts given in evidence by the adverse party</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REAL PROPERTY</name>
<meaning>Land, buildings, and other improvements affixed to the land</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REASONABLE DOUBT, BEYOND A</name>
      		<meaning> The degree of certainty required for a juror to legally find a criminal defendant guilty. An accused person is entitled to acquittal if, in the minds of the jury, 			his or her guilt has not been proved beyond a "reasonable doubt"; that state of mind of 			jurors in which they cannot say they feel a persisting conviction as to the truth of the 			charge</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REASONABLE PERSON</name>
<meaning>A phrase used to denote a hypothetical person who exercises qualities of attention, knowledge, intelligence, and judgment that society requires of its members for the protection of his or her own interest and the interests of others. Thus, the test of negligence is based on either a failure to do something that a reasonable person, guided by considerations that ordinarily regulate conduct, would do, or on the doing of something that a reasonable and prudent (wise) person would not do</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REBUTTAL</name>
      		<meaning>Evidence given to explain, counteract, or disprove facts given by the opposing counsel</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RECALL</name>
<meaning>Cancellation by a court of a warrant before its execution by the arrest of a defendant; also, a process by which a retired judge may be asked to sit on a particular case</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RECIDIVISM</name>
      		<meaning> The continued, habitual, or compulsive commission of law violations after first having been convicted of prior offenses </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RECKLESS DRIVING</name>
<meaning> Operation of a motor vehicle that shows a reckless disregard of possible consequences and indifference of other's rights </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RECOGNIZANCE</name>
<meaning> The practice which enables an accused awaiting trial to be released without posting any security other than a promise to appear before the court at the proper time.  Failure to appear in court at the proper time is a separate crime </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RECORD</name>
<meaning> All the documents and evidence plus transcripts of oral proceedings in a case </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RECUSE</name>
<meaning> The process by which a judge is disqualified from hearing a case, on his or her own motion or upon the objection of either party </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RE-DIRECT EXAMINATION</name>
<meaning> Opportunity to present rebuttal evidence after one's evidence has been subjected to cross-examination </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REDRESS</name>
      		<meaning> To set right; to remedy; to compensate; to remove the causes of a grievance</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REFEREE</name>
<meaning> A person to whom the court refers a pending case to take testimony, hear the parties, and report to the court. A referee is an officer with judicial powers who serves as an arm of the court </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REGULATION</name>
      		<meaning> A rule or order prescribed for management or government</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REHEARING</name>
<meaning> Another hearing of a civil or criminal case by the same court in which the case was originally heard </meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REJOINDER</name>
<meaning> Opportunity for the side that opened the case to offer limited response to evidence presented during the rebuttal by the opposing side </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RELEVANT</name>
<meaning> Evidence that helps to prove a point or issue in a case </meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RELINQUISHMENT</name>
<meaning> A forsaking, abandoning, renouncing, or giving over a right</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REMAND</name>
<meaning>The act of sending a case back to the trial court and ordering the trial court to conduct limited new hearings or an entirely new trial</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REMEDY</name>
<meaning>The means by which a right is enforced or the violation of a right is prevented, redressed or compensated</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REMITTITUR</name>
      		<meaning>The reduction by a judge of the damages awarded by a jury</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REMOVAL</name>
<meaning>The transfer of a state case to federal court for trial; in civil cases, because the parties are from different states; in criminal and some civil cases, because there is a significant possibility that there could not be a fair trial in state court</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REPLEVIN</name>
      		<meaning>An action for the recovery of a possession that has been wrongfully taken</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REPLY</name>
<meaning>The response by a party to charges raised in a pleading by the other party</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REPORT</name>
      		<meaning>An official or formal statement of facts or proceedings</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RESPONDENT</name>
<meaning>The party who makes an answer to a bill or other proceedings in equity; also refers to the party against whom an appeal is brought.  Sometimes called an appellee</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REST</name>
      		<meaning>A party is said to rest or rest its case when it has presented all the evidence it intends to offer</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RESTITUTION</name>
<meaning>Act of giving the equivalent for any loss, damage or injury</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RESTRAINING ORDER</name>
      		<meaning>A court order forbidding the defendant from doing any action or threatened action until a hearing on the application can be conducted</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RETAINER</name>
<meaning>Act of the client in employing the attorney or counsel. Also denotes the fee the client pays when he or she retains the attorney to act for him or her</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RETURN</name>
<meaning>A report to a judge by police on the implementation of an arrest or search warrant. Also, a report to a judge in reply to a subpoena, civil or criminal</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REVERSE</name>
      		<meaning>An action of a higher court in setting aside or revoking a lower court decision</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REVERSIBLE ERROR</name>
<meaning>A procedural error during a trial or hearing sufficiently harmful to justify reversing the judgment of a lower court. See PREJUDICIAL ERROR</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>REVOCABLE TRUST</name>
<meaning>A trust that the grantor may change or revoke</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>REVOKE</name>
      		<meaning>To annul or make void by recalling or taking back</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RIGHTS, CONSTITUTIONAL</name>
<meaning>The rights of a person guaranteed by the state or federal constitutions</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>ROBBERY</name>
      		<meaning>The act of taking money, personal property, or any other article of value that is in the possession of another done by means of force or fear</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RULE</name>
<meaning>An established standard, guide, or regulation</meaning>
	</w>
	<w>
      		<name>RULE OF COURT</name>
      		<meaning>An order made by a court having competent jurisdiction.  Rules of court are either general or special; the former are the regulations by which the practice of the 			court is governed, the latter are special orders made in particular cases</meaning>
	</w>
<w>
      		<name>RULES OF EVIDENCE</name>
<meaning>Standards governing whether evidence in a civil or criminal case is admissible</meaning>
	</w>
 </Rwords>

</root>
