<root>
<Uwords>
	<w>
      		<name>UNCONSCIONABILITY</name>
      		<meaning>An absence of meaningful choice on the part of one of the parties to a contract, and contract terms which are unreasonably favorable to the other party.</meaning>
	</w>

        <w>
      		<name>UNCONSTITUTIONAL</name>
                <meaning>A summary of a larger work, wherein the principal ideas of the larger work are contained.</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNDERCOVER</name>
                <meaning>A person participating in a secret investigation in order to acquire information about the crime without the other party realizing their identity</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNDUE INFLUENCE</name>
                <meaning>Whatever destroys free will and causes a person to do something he would not do if left to himself</meaning>
	</w>

        <w>
      		<name>UNEMPLOYMENT</name>
                <meaning>State or condition of not being employed</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNILATERAL</name>
                <meaning>One-sided, ex parte, or having a relation to only one of two or more persons or things</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNJUST ENRICHMENT, DOCTRINE OF</name>
                <meaning>The principle that one person should not be permitted to unjustly enrich himself at the expense of another, but should be required to make restitution for the property or benefit received</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNLAWFUL DETAINER</name>
                <meaning>The unjustifiable act of retaining possession without right; e.g. a tenant whose lease has expired</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>UNSECURED</name>
                <meaning> In bankruptcy proceedings, for the purposes of filing a claim, a claim is unsecured if there is no collateral, or to the extent the value of collateral is less than the amount of the debt</meaning>
	</w>

	<w>
      		<name>USURY</name>
                <meaning>Charging a higher interest rate or higher fees than the law allows</meaning>
	</w>

   </Uwords>

</root>
